研美思维采用 Vibe Coding 技术，整理分析全球医美上游企业。
Aesthetic Reflections uses Vibe Coding to organize and analyze upstream companies in global medical aesthetics.
根据最新统计数据显示，全球医美上游，除中国以外，包含 366 家企业。
According to the latest statistics, the global upstream medical aesthetics sector, excluding China, includes 366 companies.
它们覆盖 37 个国家和地区、196 个城市，研发销售覆盖 971 条产品线。
They cover 37 countries and regions, 196 cities, with R&D and sales activity spanning 971 product lines.
其中韩国 104 家企业，美国 58 家企业，意大利和法国分别 34 家。
South Korea has 104 companies, the United States has 58, while Italy and France each have 34.
前五国合计撑起约 7 成全球上游供给产品线；剩下 30 多个国家分散在长尾，全球医美产业浩瀚如星空。
The top five countries support roughly 70 percent of global upstream supply, while more than 30 other countries form a long tail, stretching the industry out like a star field.
从赛道结构看，能量源设备企业数量最多，注射针剂企业紧随其后；再生材料、植入物、耗材和诊断设备共同补全供给版图。
By category, energy-based device companies form the largest group, followed by injectables; regenerative materials, implants, consumables, and diagnostics complete the supply map.
单击国家和地区，我们可以看到每个国家的具体情况。以美国为例，58 家企业分布在 48 个城市，合计 187 条产品线。
Selecting a country or region reveals each market in detail. In the United States, 58 companies are distributed across 48 cities, with 187 product lines.
其中 9 家为上市企业。这种分布不是单点集中，而是沿东西海岸、德州与部分产业城市形成多节点网络。
Nine of them are publicly listed. This is not a single-point cluster, but a multi-node network across both coasts, Texas, and selected industry cities.
点击企业名称，我们可以进一步了解该企业的产品线分布情况。
Selecting a company name takes us further into that company's product-line distribution.
以 Allergan 为例，它位于 Irvine，主赛道为 Injectables，在全球拥有 14 条产品线与 14 个品牌，覆盖 Botox、Juvéderm、CoolSculpting 等代表性组合。
Allergan, for example, is based in Irvine, with Injectables as its primary category. Globally, it has 14 product lines and 14 brands, including Botox, Juvéderm, and CoolSculpting.
研美全球医美产业图谱，带你了解最新、最全的医美行业格局和趋势。
The Aesthetic Reflections global medical aesthetics landscape helps you read the industry's latest structure and emerging trends.
研美思维出品。
Produced by Aesthetic Reflections.